Konstantin Tenman

Software Engineer London, United Kingdom +44 7487 553781 konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

Profile

Self-motivated Software Developer with six years of experience including over four years of experience in Java development. I would like to participate in true teamwork and develop well-tested applications using a continuous delivery approach. I enjoy doing deep investigations, learning new technologies, and always looking for ways to do things better.

Programming Skills

• Languages: Java, TypeScript Technologies: Spring Framework, Angular, Hibernate, Junit, Mockito

• Tools: AWS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Git, Jenkins, Maven, IntelliJ, Redis

EXPERIENCE

• Monese

Software Engineer

London, United Kingdom

Mar 2019 - Present

- Reduced costs by systematically working to improve software performance and decrease their operating costs. For one application, it's monthly operating cost was decreased by 50%.
- Increased revenue by doggedly identifying and fixing production issues. In one case, pursuing a fix for a single customer led to identifying a significant gap in profit.
- **Pricing**: Researched regarding breaking a monolithic application into single responsibility micro-services. Refactored and developed the pricing structure of the system. Delivered business priorities by completing new annual pricing functionality on-time and without any significant issues.
- o Joint Accounts: Designed and developed the main logic around the Joint Accounts feature.

• Monese
Software Engineer
Cot 2017 - Mar 2019

- Smart Transactions: Improved scalability of micro-services by separating read and write operation of the database. Migrated gradually 120M payments to a new queue-based Java micro-service. Decreased average response time from 60ms to 5ms. Researched and introduced the new Angular 5 framework for internal tooling. Helped to improve seamless deployment in Amazon AWS.
- Recurring Payments: Designed and developed a micro-service with test coverage of up to 80%.
- Tools: Java 8-11, Angular, TypeScript, Grails, Scala, Docker, Amazon AWS, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, Google
 API, Mockito, Junit, Redis, AWS, CloudWatch, New Relic, Jenkins, Git, Intellij, Groovy, Testcontainers, Maven,
 Liquibase, Bootstrap, macOS

• Codeborne Tallinn, Estonia
Software Developer Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

- Developed an internet banking website which is used by 2M customers.
- Developed a responsive internet banking website for desktop and mobile platforms.
- o Tools: Java 8, RiotJS, Selenium, Mockito, TDD, Intellij, Agile, extreme programming, Play! Framework, Ubuntu

• Knowit

Tallinn, Estonia

- Developed a full-stack web-based application where users create services and search for them through Google Maps.
- **Technologies**: AngularJS, Java 8, Docker, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JHipster, Sass, CSS3, HTML5, Protractor, Maven, Liquibase, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Ubuntu, Git

EDUCATION

Software Developer

• Tallinn University Estonia

Jun 2016 - Apr 2017